IA NAIR NOONAN

1834 Crenshaw Street San Diego, CA 92105 asha.nair.noonan@gmail.com 413-695-4035

CURRENTLY

I am a student at Softstack Factory due to finish in September 2016. I have eight years of experience in the non-profit and education sectors. Supervisory experience as well as strong collaboration and communication skills. Specialized study and background in mobile app development and information technology. Experience and leadership in working with diverse populations, from work with disenfranchised constituents both professionally and through volunteer work.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Arts, Communications, cum laude, May 2011, Simmons College Information Technology and Poltical Science minors Study Abroad

Universidad de Guanajuato, Guanajuato, Mexico August 2010 Universidad San Ignacio de Loyola, Cusco, Peru, January-May 2009

ACHIEVEMENTS

TECHINCAL SKILLS/ **ABILITIES** ■ Presidential Recognition Award ■ Dean's List ■ Member, Lambda Pi Eta, National Communications Honor Society

■ StrongLoop

■ GitHub

■ HTML and CSS ■ MvSQL ■ JavaScript ■ MS SQL ■ MongoDB ■ Python ■ Express.js ■ Ionic Framework ■ Angular.js

■ Microsoft Office Suite ■ Balsamiq ■ Adobe Design Suite ■ Pivotal Tracker ■ Google Fusion Tables ■ Video Editina ■ Social Media Management

■ Windows/Macintosh OS ■ Graphic Design ■ UI/UX Design ■ Fluent in Spanish ■ Public speaking

WORK EXPERIENCE

2011- Present

■ Freelance Design

■ Node.js

Graphic Designer - Freelance design work to provide identity, print and web design for a variety of clients. Select work: City Heights Town Council - Website design, creation and maintenance

> American Red Cross - Promotional posters and brochures for outreach events, both print and online Measles Initiative - Created promtional handouts and designed fundraising materials Craigs Doors, A Home Association, Inc. -Developed and designed logo, business cards and letterhead Alternative Spring Break: Simmons Builds -Developed and designed logo and promotional materials The Women's Center -Logo for The Beauty Campaign

2012 – 2016 ■ Legal Aid Society of San Diego, Inc.

SSI Advocate - Conducted initial and follow-up interviews of SSI applicants and clients. Prepared forms and gathered documentation for submission to the Social Security Administration. Requested and evaluated medical evidence. Basic and routine factual investigation and legal research. Prepared memorandums, letters and standard legal documents. Developed and maintained good working relationships with a variety of healthcare providers, government and social service agencies. Represented clients at administrative hearings. Assisted with community outreach and education.

2011 – 2012 ■ American Red Cross, San Diego, CA

AmeriCorps Outreach Associate - Disaster preparedness and CPR/First Aid training for local community groups of up to 400 people. Provided direct service to clients of the ARC as a Disaster Action Team Leader and Disaster Duty Officer. Volunteered with International Services for Refugee Community Outreach. Special projects included rewriting and redesigning volunteer workshops, creating all visual and print media requested by the chapter.

2008 – 2011 ■ Simmons College, Boston, MA

Teaching Assistant for Communications Technologies and Visual Communications courses - Taught classes of up to 35 students in units covering iMovie, Photoshop, InDesign, Illustrator and Dreamweaver.

Communications Lab Monitor - Managed budget of \$250,000, authorized printing projects, fixed equipment, assisted professors and students, led training workshops.

Technical Administrative Assistant - Staffed IT Help Desk, provided technical assistance to faculty and students, provided office support to the technology department, assisted and supported administrative managers and directors in their daily tasks, maintained and managed technical files and records in an organized manner, troubleshot and resolved customers' complex technical problems.

2010 **Democratic National Committee**, Washington, DC

New Media Department -Worked with Chairs, Director of Communications, and campaign managers to promote online organizing, advocacy, fundraising and communication. Created social media and email content, monitored and reported social media trends. Awarded lead intern commendation.

2009 – 2010 ■ The Warming Place Shelter, Amherst, MA

Shift Supervisor - Supervised 5 employees and 15 clients and managed opening and closing of homeless shelter.

ACTIVITIES ■ Classical Indian Dance ■ Website Design/management ■ International travel ■ Tennis ■ Social Justice work